<chapter>
  <title>Introduction to Songbee</title>
  <para>
      Songbee is an application designed to be used in churches for
      the projection of worship song lyrics. Instead of using hymn
      books, churches can use a data projector and a computer running
      Songbee to display the words to hymns and songs.
  </para>
  <para>
      Songbee is particularly designed for the Japanese church. It
      handles Japanese text, and particularly the display of
      <foreignphrase>furigana</foreignphrase>, in ways that other
      similar applications (Easislides, openlp.org, Opensong and
      Lyricue) do not.
  </para>
  <sect1>
    <title>Requirements</title>
    <para>
      In order to use Songbee, you will need to have a dual-monitor
      set up. That is to say, your computer must be able to send video
      to two different monitors: one will be your ordinary
      workstation, and the second will be a projector or
      closed-circuit television system to display the lyrics to your
      congregation. 
    </para>
    <para>
      If you have a laptop, you normally have the ability to plug in
      an external monitor - plug your projector into the monitor
      output. If you have a desktop PC, you may need to install a
      second video card. Once you have done this and plugged the
      projector into the second output, you will need to configure
      your operating system to display in multi-monitor mode. 
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
	<term>Windows</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>For Windows computers, follow these steps to turn on
multiple monitor support:</para>
	  <orderedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>Right-click on the desktop.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>Click the <command>Settings</command> tab.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>Click the <command>Display</command> list and
select the second monitor.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>Select <command>Extend my Windows desktop onto
this monitor</command> and click <command>OK</command>.</para>
	    </listitem>
	  </orderedlist>
          <para>Note that on some brands of laptop the above
            instructions do not work and you will need to use the
            software that comes with the laptop.</para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
	<term>Mac OS X</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>On a Macintosh:</para>
	  <orderedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>Open <application>System
Preferences</application>.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>Click on the <command>Displays</command>
icon.</para>
	    </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      <para>Click the <command>Detect Displays</command> button</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>Turn off display mirroring.</para>
	    </listitem>
	  </orderedlist>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Features</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	<para>Compilation of custom playlists</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>Easy to set up, and available on many platforms</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>Ability to create and edit songs</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>Ability to import and export databases of songs</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Future Features</title>
    <para>
      While Songbee does not intend to compete with some of the more
established projects mentioned above, the following features are
anticipated in future releases:
</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	<para>Ability to select alternative song databases</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>Customization of the main worship display</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>Export song lyrics as Microsoft Word document</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>Drag-and-drop interface to adding songs to the playlist</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      It is unlikely that Songbee will support display of Powerpoint or
      multimedia files, but Powerpoint can be run at the same time as
      songbee, and if you start a powerpoint show it will open over the top
      of songbee's output.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Technical details</title>
    <para>
      Songbee is implemented in XUL and Javascript using the Mozilla
      platform, the same platform used by Firefox and Thunderbird, and
      so would run on any operating system supported by Mozilla. The
      database of songs and playlists are stored in an SQLite database
      using the <classname>storage</classname> extension; once a user
      runs Songbee for the first time, Songbee creates a profile
      directory for them and copies in a SQLite database
      file. Individual songs are stored in a custom XML format.
    </para>
  </sect1>
</chapter>
