<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
          "/sw/share/xml/dtd/docbookx/4.2.0/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>Managing Song Databases</title>
  <para>
  </para>
  <sect1 id="song.editor">
    <title>Adding and editing songs</title>
    <para>
      To add a new song, click on the "add song" toolbutton at the top
      of the main playlist window. You can edit an existing song by
right-clicking<footnote>
	<para>
(Mac: <keycap>Ctrl</keycap>-clicking.
</para>
      </footnote>
      on the song name while editing a playlist:
    </para>
    <figure>
      <title>Editing an existing song</title>
      <mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
	  <imagedata width="200" fileref="images/edit-popup.png"/>
	</imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
     Once you have selected a song to edit, or chosen "Add Song", you
     will be taken to the song editor window. The song editor window
     looks like this:
    </para>
    <figure>
      <title>Editing an existing song</title>
      <mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
	  <imagedata width="350" fileref="images/edit-song.png"/>
	</imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
     This consists of two parts; the right hand part is an
automatically-generated preview. The left part is where you enter all
the details of the current song: its title, key, year, and so on. The
box at the bottom is where you enter the lyrics. The lyrics are
entered using a couple of conventions:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	<para> Verses, choruses and bridges are entered as paragraphs,
with a blank line separating them. Lines breaks are preserved inside a
verse. To begin a chorus or bridge, the first line should be
"<userinput>Chorus:</userinput>" or "<userinput>Bridge:</userinput>"
respectively, with the text of the chorus/bridge immediately following
and with no blank line in between.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>When entering Japanese furigana, do so like this:
	<userinput>(&#x6F22;|&#x304B;&#x3093;)</userinput>. That is to
	say, place the expression in brackets; put the main text
	first, then a pipe sign (|), and then the furigana. The
	brackets and pipe sign must be entered in romaji. The furigana
	will be displayed above the main text. You should be able to
	see this on the preview.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Importing and exporting songs</title>
    <para>
     You may import and export song libraries to a special Songbee
     library format. (For interested developers, it's not that
     special, it's just ordinary XML and you'll be able to work out
     how it goes by looking at it.) See <link
     linkend="playlist.import">the playlist window menu</link>.
    </para>
  </sect1>
</chapter>
