<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
          "/sw/share/xml/dtd/docbookx/4.2.0/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>Managing Song Databases</title>
  <para>
  </para>
  <sect1 id="song.editor">
    <title>Adding and editing songs</title>
    <para>
      To add a new song, click on the "add song" toolbutton at the top
      of the main playlist window. You can edit an existing song by
right-clicking<footnote>
	<para>
(Mac: <keycap>Ctrl</keycap>-clicking.
</para>
      </footnote>
      on the song name while editing a playlist:
    </para>
    <figure>
      <title>Editing an existing song</title>
      <mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
	  <imagedata width="200" fileref="images/edit-popup.png"/>
	</imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
     Once you have selected a song to edit, or chosen "Add Song", you
     will be taken to the song editor window. The song editor window
     looks like this:
    </para>
    <figure>
      <title>Editing an existing song</title>
      <mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
	  <imagedata width="350" fileref="images/edit-song.png"/>
	</imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
     This consists of two parts; the right hand part is an
automatically-generated preview. The left part is where you enter all
the details of the current song: its title, key, year, and so on. The
box at the bottom is where you enter the lyrics. The lyrics are
entered using a couple of conventions:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	<para> Verses, choruses and bridges are entered as paragraphs,
with a blank line separating them. Lines breaks are preserved inside a
verse. To begin a chorus or bridge, the first line should be
"<userinput>Chorus:</userinput>" or "<userinput>Bridge:</userinput>"
respectively, with the text of the chorus/bridge immediately following
and with no blank line in between.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>When entering Japanese furigana, do so like this:
	<userinput>(&#x6F22;|&#x304B;&#x3093;)</userinput>. That is to
	say, place the expression in brackets; put the main text
	first, then a pipe sign (|), and then the furigana. The
	brackets and pipe sign must be entered in romaji. The furigana
	will be displayed above the main text. You should be able to
	see this on the preview.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <sect2>
      <title>Metadata</title> 

      <para>"Metadata" means "data about data" or "information about
      information". It's the name for additional data you can add to
      your songs to help categorise them. Each song is guaranteed to
      have some lyrics and a title, but anything else you want to add
      is up to you.</para> 

      <para>Metadata in Songbee has a <emphasis>key</emphasis> and a
      <emphasis>value</emphasis>. <literal>title</literal> is a very
      common key, and the song's title is the
      value. <literal>language</literal> is another common key, and
      common values include "Japanese", "English" and so on. But you
      can make up whatever keys you like.
      </para>

      <para>For instance, when you're inputting old Japanese hymns,
      you might want to tell Songbee what number they are in each of
      the common hymnbooks. So <literal>sanbika</literal>,
      <literal>seika</literal> and <literal>shinseika</literal> are
      likely keys to use, and the number of the song in the songbook
      would make good values.</para>

      <para>To add a piece of metadata to a song, right click on the
      table in the top-left of the song edit page and choose "Add
      Metadata". You are then presented with the following pop-up
      panel:</para>
      <figure>
	<title>Adding metadata</title>
      <mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
	  <imagedata width="350" fileref="images/add-metadata.png"/>
	</imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>The drop-down menu will allow you to choose key names that
      Songbee already knows. If you want to add something different,
      simply type in your own key.</para>

      <para>Currently Songbee doesn't do very much with the metadata
      you add, apart from the "language" and "translation". However,
      in the near future, you will be able to search and add songs to
      playlists based on metadata, so it's in your interests to add
      whatever metadata you want when creating songs. </para>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Translated songs</title>

      <para>Songbee supports multilingual worship if it has a database
      where songs are tagged with translation metadata. If you have a
      song (let's call it "X") which is a translation of another song
      "Y", you can tell Songbee about this by editing "X",
      right-clicking on the metadata section and choosing
      <literal>Mark as translation</literal>. Songbee will then ask
      you to select the song that "X" is a translation of; you should
      choose "Y" from the list.
</para>

      <para>For translations to work, you need to tag both songs with
      their language. If this is not done before you choose
      <literal>Mark as translation</literal>, then Songbee will prompt
      you for the languages.</para>

      <para>Songbee also supports songs being translated several
      times. It has no concept of which song is the "original" - if
      you tell it that "Y" is a translation of "X" and that "Z" is a
      translation of "Y", then it will connect X, Y and Z all
      together.</para>

    </sect2>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Importing and exporting songs</title> <para>Currently you
    may import and export song libraries to a special Songbee library
    format. (For interested developers, it's not that special, it's
    just ordinary XML and you'll be able to work out how it goes by
    looking at it.) See <link linkend="playlist.import">the playlist
    window menu</link>.
    </para>
  </sect1>
</chapter>
