<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
          "/sw/share/xml/dtd/docbookx/4.2.0/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>The Live Interface</title>
  <para>
    When you click <command>Go</command> on a playlist, you are
    taken to Songbee's "live" interface. This consists of two
    windows. The first window should appear on your projector.
  </para>
  <note>
    <para>It <emphasis>should</emphasis> appear on your projector. At
    the moment, it won't, and you have to drag it there
    manually. We're working on this.
    </para>
  </note>
  <para>
   The second window is the <firstterm>live console</firstterm>. It
looks like this:
  </para>
  <figure>
    <title>The live console</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
	<imagedata width="200" fileref="images/live-console.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <para>
    On the left you see the current song. The portion in blue is
    currently visible on the projector. Usually this covers an entire
    verse, but when the verse is longer than one screenful, as in the
    example above, only the visible lines are highlighted.
</para>
  <para>
    The next song in the playlist is displayed on the right, and under
    that, the current playlist. At the bottom of the window are the
    buttons for controlling Songbee with the mouse.
  </para>
  <sect1>
    <title>Navigating with keystrokes</title>
    <para>
     However, the recommended way of controlling Songbee is with the
keyboard. Even if you are used to using your mouse to control your
computer, you will find that using the keyboard allows you to move to
the right portion of the right song much more quickly in reaction to
things that your worship leader may unexpectedly do!
    </para>
    <para>
     Here are the keys used to control Songbee:
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><keycap>&#x2190;</keycap></term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>Go to the previous song in the playlist.</para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><keycap>&#x2192;</keycap></term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>Go to the next song in the playlist.</para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><keycap>&#x2191;</keycap></term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>This will return to the previous verse, chorus or
bridge within the current song.</para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><keycap>&#x2193;</keycap></term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>If, as in the example above, only a portion of the
	  lines of a verse can fit on the projector display, this key
	  (cursor down) will scroll down the verse. Once the last line
	  is displayed, or if the entire verse can fit on the display
	  at once, then this key will jump to the next portion of the
	  song shown in the left-hand pane.</para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><keycap>PgDn</keycap></term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>Page down will jump, rather than scroll, to the next
portion of the verse to be displayed.</para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><keycap>1</keycap>, <keycap>2</keycap>, <keycap>3</keycap>, etc.</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>Jump to the corresponding verse of the current song.</para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><keycap>v</keycap>, <keycap>c</keycap>, <keycap>b</keycap></term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>Jump to the next verse, chorus or bridge. A <firstterm>chorus</firstterm> is displayed in the console in a slightly narrower margins than a verse; a <firstterm>bridge</firstterm> is displayed in italics.</para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><keycap>n</keycap></term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>Goes to the "next" bit of the song - if your song has
	  a chorus, it will alternate between verses and choruses; if
	  it has just verses, it will go from one verse to the next;
	  otherwise, it won't do anything.</para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><keycap>Esc</keycap></term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>The escape key "pauses" the display, removing the text
	  from the projector. The highlight in the current song pane
	  turns from blue to yellow to remind you that the display is
	  paused. Pressing escape again will unpause the display; you
	  may change to a difference verse or a different song while
	  the display is paused.</para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Navigating with the mouse</title>
    <para>
      If you must navigate with the mouse, you can use the left and
      right buttons at the bottom of the screen to change songs; you
      may also click on a song in the song list to jump to that song
      directly. Clicking on a portion of a song in the left-hand
      window will cause Songbee to display that portion.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Multilingual worship</title> <para>Songbee supports
    environments where worship happens in more than one language. If
    the current song is translated into other languages, the names of
    the translations appear in a bar at the bottom of your
    console. Clicking on a name brings up the song of the appropriate
    language.</para> <para>To learn how to mark songs as translations,
    see the chapter on editing.</para>
  </sect1>
</chapter>
