<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
          "/sw/share/xml/dtd/docbookx/4.2.0/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>Managing Playlists</title>
  <para>
    A <firstterm>playlist</firstterm> is a collection of songs to be
    played in a worship session. Songbee currently assumes that the
    list of songs is known before the worship begins. Using Songbee
    has two phases: creating and editing the playlist before worship,
    and moving between the songs during the worship time.
  </para>
  <sect1>
    <title>The playlist interface</title>
    <para>
    When Songbee starts, you will see a window like this:
    </para>
    <figure>
      <title>Playlist list</title>
      <mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
	  <imagedata width="200" fileref="images/playlist-list.png"/>
	</imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
    This shows all the playlists in your library, together with the
songs in each playlist. At the top of the window are three toolbuttons:
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><command>Add Playlist</command></term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
            This creates a new playlist, prompts you for a name, and
            takes you to the <link linkend="playlist.editor">playlist
            editor</link>.
          </para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><command>Add Song</command></term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
            This creates a new song, and takes you to the <link
            linkend="song.editor">song editor.</link>
</para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><command>Import songs</command></term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
            This allows you to import songs from a Songbee song
            library file; that is to say, if you have a file
            containing additional songs in Songbee format, this option
            will add them to your database.
</para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para>
      Alongside each playlist's title are three buttons:
      <command>Go</command> will take you to the main "live"
      screen; <command>Edit</command> will take you to the playlist
      editor for this playlist; <command>Delete</command> will delete
      the playlist from the system. It does not delete the songs from
      the database, just the running order for an occasion.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1 id="playlist.editor">
    <title>Playlist Editor</title>
    <para>
      The playlist editor is where you put together the list of songs
      that are going to be used in the worship time. The playlist
      editor shows the current songs in the playlist, and the avaiable
      songs, like this:
    </para>
    <figure>
      <title>Playlist editor</title>
      <mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
	  <imagedata width="200" fileref="images/playlist-edit.png"/>
	</imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
     The playlist editor consists of the following features: the
current playlist, on the left; the list of available songs, on the
right; the preview pane, displaying the currently chosen song, below
the song list; at the bottom, the search bar.
    </para>
    <sect2>
      <title>Creating a playlist</title>
    <para>
      To construct the playlist, find the song you want in the song
list. You'll see a preview of the currently selected song in the song list.
To add the song to your playlist, double-click on the song in the song list.
    </para>
      <para>
      You can re-order your playlist by dragging songs up and down the
list. To remove a song from the playlist, click on it to select it,
and press the <keycap>Delete</keycap> key.
      </para>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Searching for a song</title>
      <para>
       To find a song in the song list, you may either scroll through,
       or use the search interface at the bottom of the window. To use
       this, type in part of the song you are looking for, and Songbee
       will narrow down the song list to only include songs that match
your search. Songbee uses the following strategies to find your song:
</para>
      <itemizedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>First, it looks for songs with your search text in the
title.</para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>If no songs match, then it looks for songs with your
search text in the first line.</para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>Finally, it searches for songs which contain the
search text anywhere in their lyrics</para>
	</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
       Songbee's search function generally does what you want, so if
you cannot find the song you are looking for, keep typing in words
until it appears in the song list.
</para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
</chapter>
