<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
          "/sw/share/xml/dtd/docbookx/4.2.0/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>Managing Playlists</title>
  <para>
    A <firstterm>playlist</firstterm> is a collection of songs to be
    played in a worship session. Songbee currently assumes that the
    list of songs is known before the worship begins. (Although it
    does give you the ability to insert "unexpected" songs during
    worship time. So at least one song must be known!)  Using Songbee
    has two phases: creating and editing the playlist before worship,
    and moving between the songs during the worship time.
  </para>
  <sect1>
    <title>The playlist interface</title>
    <para>
    When Songbee starts, you will see a window like this:
    </para>
    <figure>
      <title>Playlist list</title>
      <mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
	  <imagedata width="200" fileref="images/playlist-list.png"/>
	</imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
    This shows all the playlists in your library, together with the
songs in each playlist. At the top of the window are a set of menus:
    </para>
    <variablelist>

      <varlistentry>
	<term><command>File</command>
</term>
	<listitem>
	  <variablelist>
	    <varlistentry>
	      <term>Import Songs</term>
	      <listitem>
		<para>
            This allows you to import songs from a Songbee song
            library file; that is to say, if you have a file
            containing additional songs in Songbee format, this option
            will add them to your database.
</para>
	      </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	      <term>Export Songs</term>
	      <listitem>
		<para>
            This will export your entire songs database as a Songbee
            song library file. If you enter a lot of the songs you use
            from week to week and then export your library and send
            the resulting file to the Songbee maintainer, perhaps
            together we can build up a good library of songs used by
            the Japanese church. Hopefully we'll then include the
            expanded library file in Songbee distributions in the
            future, making Songbee more useful for everyone, at least
            until the copyright police come to stop us worshipping
            freely.
		</para>
	      </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	      <term>Preferences</term>
	      <listitem>
		<para> This allows you to determine how you would like
		the default display to appear: you can change the font
		sizes, spacing, colours, set a background image and so
		on. </para>
		<note>
		  <title>For the technically inclined</title>
		  <para>If you want more control over how the display
		  appears, and you speak CSS, then you can create your
		  own display preferences manually. Simply make some
		  changes and save the preferences, then look in your
		  profile directory.</para>
		  <para>On the Mac, the profile directory is <filename>Library:Application Support:Songbee:Profiles</filename>. Inside that directory you will find a file called <filename>user.projector.css</filename> which contains all your customizations. For the base CSS file, see <filename>Contents:Resources:Chrome:songbee:css:projector.css</filename> in your Songbee application bundle. (Right-click on the Songbee application and select <command>Show package contents</command> to find this file.</para>
		  <para>On Windows, the relevant directories are <filename>%XXX%/Simon Cozens/Songbee</filename> and <filename>\Program Files\Songbee\chrome\songbee\css</filename>.</para>
		</note>
	      </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	      <term>Exit</term>
	      <listitem>
		<para>Ends the Songbee program.</para>
	      </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	  </variablelist>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
	<term><command>Create</command></term>
	<listitem>
	  <variablelist>
	    <varlistentry>
	      <term>Add Playlist</term>
	      <listitem>
		<para>
            This creates a new playlist, prompts you for a name, and
            takes you to the <link linkend="playlist.editor">playlist
            editor</link>.
          </para>
	      </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	  </variablelist>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para>
      Alongside each playlist's title are three buttons:
      <command>Go</command> will take you to the main "live"
      screen; <command>Edit</command> will take you to the playlist
      editor for this playlist; <command>Delete</command> will delete
      the playlist from the system. It does not delete the songs from
      the database, just the running order for an occasion.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1 id="playlist.editor">
    <title>Playlist Editor</title>
    <para>
      The playlist editor is where you put together the list of songs
      and other items that are going to be used in the worship
      time. It is also where you can add new songs to the library.
    </para>
    <para>
      The playlist editor shows the current songs in the playlist, and
      the available songs, like this:
    </para>
    <figure>
      <title>Playlist editor</title>
      <mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
	  <imagedata width="200" fileref="images/playlist-edit.png"/>
	</imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
     The playlist editor consists of the following features: the
     current playlist, on the left; the list of available songs (the
     "library") on the right; the preview pane, displaying the
     currently chosen song, below the library; at the bottom, the
     search bar.
    </para>
    <sect2>
      <title>Creating a playlist</title>
    <para>
      To construct the playlist, find the song you want in the library
      When you select a song you'll see a preview of it below the
      library. To add the song to your playlist, double-click on the
      currently selected song, or drag it into position in the
      playlist.
    </para>
      <para>
      You can re-order your playlist by dragging songs up and down the
      list. To remove a song from the playlist, click on it to select
      it, and press the <keycap>Delete</keycap> key or drag it outside
      of the playlist pane.
      </para>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Searching for a song</title>
      <para>
       To find a song in the song list, you may either scroll through,
       or use the search interface at the bottom of the window. To use
       this, type in part of the song you are looking for, and Songbee
       will narrow down the song list to only include songs that match
your search. Songbee uses the following strategies to find your song:
</para>
      <itemizedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>First, it looks for songs with your search text in the
title.</para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>If no songs match, then it looks for songs with your
search text in the first line.</para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>Finally, it searches for songs which contain the
search text anywhere in their lyrics</para>
	</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
       Songbee's search function generally does what you want, so if
you cannot find the song you are looking for, keep typing in words
until it appears in the song list.
</para>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Adding other kinds of content to your playlist</title>
      <para>
       Songbee does not just support songs: you may add web site
       display, Bible passage display and hopefully (in the future)
       other types of information, to your playlist.
      </para>
      <para>To do this, use the <command>Create</command> menu.</para>
      <para>
       Selecting <command>Song</command> will take you to <link
       linkend="song.editor">the song editor</link>, allowing you to
       add a song which is not currently in your library.
      </para>
      <para>
       If you select <command>Bible passage</command> you will be
       prompted for a Bible reference. This can be a verse of range of
       verses, and unambiguous abbreviations of book names are
       supported. The passage will be looked up and displayed at the
       appropriate point in the worship time.
</para>
      <warning>
	<para>Bible passage display currently requires an active Internet
	connection; passages are looked up in the online version of the
	ESV. We know this is not ideal, but it is a start and making
	it work well will be a lot of work.</para>
      </warning>
      <para>
       If you select the <command>Web page</command> option, you will
       be prompted for a web site URL. This web page will be displayed
       during worship time. If you move the mouse pointer over to the
       projector window, you can navigate the page, following links
       and so on, as if in a web browser. The URL may also be a
       <literal>file:///</literal> address to a file on your local
       system. This can be a useful, if not ideal, way to display
       videos and so on.
      </para>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Per-playlist display preferences</title>
      <para>
        By default, all playlists look the same when they are
        displayed at worship time. However, you may change the display
        of individual playlists by selecting
        <command>Preferences</command> from the
        <command>File</command> menu in this playlist editor window.
      </para>
      <note>
	<para>We have been asked if Songbee could support per-slide
	customization, for example allowing different songs to have different
	backgrounds. Much though we dislike putting artificial
	restrictions on what the user can do with Songbee, this one we
	won't support, because we think it makes it too easy for the
	result to look tacky and horrible. Songbee handles your
	worship with <emphasis>class</emphasis>.
	</para>
      </note>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Save as Word</title> 

      <para>For those who wish to print out their song lyrics as a
      handout, you can select the <command>Save as Word</command>
      option from the <command>File</command> menu. You will then be
      prompted for a file name, and Songbee will produce a Microsoft
      Word document containing all the song names and their
      lyrics.</para>
      <note>
	<title>For the technically inclined</title> 

	<para>This isn't actually a Word document, since writing Word
	documents by hand is hard; it's just a HTML file, which Word
	imports unquestioningly. You can therefore use this document
	for other purposes too. </para>
      </note>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
</chapter>
